# HAZIM SULAIMAN

hajimss.github.io

Singaporean | hazim897@gmail.com | +65 97221283

# **EDUCATION**

# NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (MECHANICAL ENGINEERING)

Aug 2016 - May 2020

Technical electives:
 Programming
 Methodology (C), Data
 Structures and
 Algorithms (C++)

# HANYANG UNIVERSITY (KOREA)

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

• Summer Exchange

# **SKILLS**

#### DATA

Pandas, Apache Kafka, Kafka-Python

#### **DATABASES**

MySQL, MongoDB

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

HTML, CSS, ReactJS, Flask, Web2Py

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Python, Javascript, C++

### MISC

Git, Figma

#### **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

English, Malay

# LINKS

#### **GITHUB**

hajimss

#### **LINKEDIN**

hazim-sulaiman

#### **PORTFOLIO SITE**

hajimss.github.io

#### **PROFILE**

Software Engineering / Web Development Enthusiast, who enjoys building websites, applications and ML projects as hobby. Currently working as a Software Developer and does side tech projects after work. Continuously learns libraries and frameworks associated with Python, C++, Javascript, both frontend and backend.

Previously, a firefighter who served the community, and a mechanical engineer in offshore, oil & gas technology.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

UBS | Oct 2020 - Present

- Technologies used: Python, Pandas, Jupyter, Kafka, SQL, Raspberry Pi, Web2Py etc
- Handled Data Analytics and Data workflows (ETL)

#### FINTECHSG PROGRAMME

National University of Singapore. | Aug 2020 - Oct 2020

- Frontend and Backend Web development (Javascript, React, Database: MySQL, MongoDB), and Containerisation
- Data Analytics and AlgoTrading (QuantConnect)
- UI/UX on Figma.
- Blockchain (Smart Contracts using Solidity)

#### **IOT/ROBOTICS ENGINEER**

Catalyst Connector Pte Ltd | Jan 2019 - May 2019

- To alleviate the burden of labourers, led a team of six to designed an autonomous grass cutting robot that is functional and reduce labour cost
- Supervised shell modelling and manufacturing, using Solidworks and machineries; implemented structural analysis with Ansys

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

UBS | Oct 2020 - Present

- Department: Network Services and Automation
- Analyse data of worldwide UBS servers and render solutions to optimise usage
- Created Proof of concept for the application of Apache Kafka on the Change Data Capture of server network

#### **MECHANICAL ENGINEER (INTERN)**

Schlumberger | Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

- Supported SWTC's new product development department
- Created CAD (Computer-Aided Design) models, assemblies and drawings and assisted in physical assembles